[{"Question": "When was the first Ancient Olympic Games held?", "Options": ["776 B.C.", "776 A.C.", 1986.0, 2008.0], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "Why were the Ancient Games stopped?", "Options": ["Because they got bored", "They was no one to play the sports", "They didn't have any money", "Greece was conquered and became part of the Roman Empire"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "When and which country was the Modern Olympic Games restarted again?", "Options": ["Baron Pierre de Coubertin", "Greece", "Australia", "France"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "Were females allowed to compete in the Ancient games?", "Options": ["Yes", "No", "Only the rich", "Only the poor"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "The Olympic Games were first staged in honour/honor of", "Options": ["Plato ", "Zeus", "Alexander the Great", "Jesus"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "The five colors of the rings are ?", "Options": ["Black, white, yellow, red, blue", "Black, yellow, orange, red, blue", "Black, blue, yellow, green, and red", "Green, white,pink,green,black"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "Which Greek Goddess (of victory) has traditionally appeared on Olympic medals in the modern age:", "Options": ["Adidas", "Gola", "Nike", "Puma"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "Which of these is not one of the five Olympic rings", "Options": ["Blue", "Green", "Red", "Purple"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "Modern Olympic 'gold' medals are predominantly", "Options": ["Gold", "Silver", "Bronze", "Brass"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "The IOC stipulates, due to \"...the unfortunate demise of several (What?) sitting on the edge of the Olympic cauldron at the Opening Ceremony of the (1988) Games in Seoul...\" that these creatures are used only symbolically in opening ceremonies", "Options": ["Butterflies", "Fireflies", "Doves", "Eagles"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "The Olympic Games were named after Olympia, a (What?) in Ancient Greece", "Options": ["Sanctuary", "Mountain", "Goddess", "Exhibition centre"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "In the early Olympics, a boxer who ______ automatically (but not essentially) became winner", "Options": ["Cried", "Fainted", "Bled", "Died"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "The first venue for the 'modern' Olympic games revived in 1896 by French educator Baron de Coubertin (Pierre de Fredi), after being banned by the Romans in c.AD395, was", "Options": ["Paris", "Athens", "London", "Rome"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "Which nation traditionally leads the Olympics Games Opening Ceremony Parade", "Options": ["The host nation", "The previous host nation", "The next host nation", "Greece"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "Which sport in the ancient Olympic Games allowed finger breaking?", "Options": ["Chariot racing", "Wrestling", "Pankration", "Pankration"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "The Olympic flame is lit in a ritual at Olympia.", "Options": [1], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "Which were the first three events that the athletes competed in at the Ancient Olympic Games till 720 BC?", "Options": ["200 yard, 400 yard foot race and a variable length foot race", "400 yard, 800 yard and a variable length foot race", "100 yard, 200 yard and 400 yard foot race", "200 yard, 800 yard and 1600 yard foot race"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "The Pankration was an event introduced to the Ancient Olympic Games around 648 BC. It combined which of the following?", "Options": ["\u00a0Boxing and Running", "Boxing and Wrestling", "\u00a0Running and Jumping", "Discus and Boxing"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "Aside from Chariot Racing, which other equestrian event, introduced around 648 BC, was held in the Ancient Olympic Games?", "Options": ["Jumping", "Cross Country", "Dressage", "Horse Racing"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "Which was put in place by the Greeks before and during all the Ancient Olympic festivals?", "Options": ["A public holiday", "\u00a0A truce", "A ban on drinking", "A ban on taxes"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "What was the great Sanctuary of Zeus, the setting for the Olympic Games, called by the Ancient Greeks?", "Options": ["Altis", "Tumulus", "Alsos", "Megaron"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "Approximately how many years after Theodosius I abolished the Olympic Games because of their pagan influence in 393 AD, did Pierre de Coubertin begin their revival?", "Options": [500.0, 2000.0, 1000.0, 1500.0], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "In which year were the very first modern Olympic Games held, and where?", "Options": ["1900, Paris", "1896, Athens", "1904, St Louis", "1892, Athens"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "In which year was the official Olympic Flag first used at the modern Olympic Games?", "Options": [1916.0, 1920.0, 1912.0, 1900.0], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "The Olympic flame was first lit during which year of the modern era?", "Options": [1920.0, 1900.0, 1928.0, 1904.0], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "At which Modern Olympic Games did they first use electronic timing devices and a public address system?", "Options": ["1912 in Stockholm", "1896 in Athens", "1928 in Amsterdam", "1908 in London"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "In which year was the modern Marathon 'standardised' to a length of 42,195 metres?", "Options": [1928.0, 1908.0, 1924.0, 1916.0], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "In 1932, the second of the modern Olympic Games to be held in the USA were in Los Angeles, with which of the following not being introduced for the first time?", "Options": ["Olympic village", "Photo-finish cameras", "Televising of the Games", "Victory platforms"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "In which of the following three years were the Olympic Games not held?", "Options": ["1912, 1936 and 1940", "1916, 1936 and 1940", "1936, 1940 and 1944", "1916, 1940 and 1944"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "In which year of the Modern Olympics were the Winter Games added?", "Options": [1916.0, 1920.0, 1924.0, 1936.0], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "In which year were Olympic medals restored to Native American, Jim Thorpe?", "Options": [1980.0, 1982.0, 1990.0, 2000.0], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "In which three years of the Modern Olympic Games were there boycotts by various Olympic teams?", "Options": ["1976, 1980 and 1988", "1972, 1976 and 1984", "1976, 1980 and 1984", "1968, 1976 and 1980"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "\u00a0Where is the headquarters of the International Olympic Committee, the IOC?", "Options": ["Lausanne", "London", "Los Angeles", "Sydney"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "In which cities were the modern Olympic Games due to be held/scheduled during the 'war years', i.e., 1916, 1940, and 1944?", "Options": ["Helsinki, Berlin and London", "Berlin, Paris and Tokyo", "Berlin, Tokyo and Helsinki", "Paris, Tokyo and Helsinki"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "What was the first\u00a0team sport\u00a0to be added to the Olympics?", "Options": ["Football", "Rugby", "Hockey", "Baseball"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "\u00a0In what year did it become\u00a0illegal\u00a0for athletes at the Olympic Games to use drugs to enhance their performance during competition?", "Options": [1912.0, 1956.0, 1967.0, 1979.0], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "\u00a0The first\u00a0black athlete\u00a0to compete at the Olympics was from which country?", "Options": ["USA", "Australia", "France", "Italy"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "\u00a0Which of these countries has won at\u00a0least one gold medal\u00a0at every modern Olympic Games?", "Options": ["Great Britain", "USA", "Greece", "Australia"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "Who was the first Olympic gymnast to score a perfect 10?\u00a0", "Options": ["Mary Lou Retton", "Nandia Comaneci", "Cathy Rigby", "Shannon Miller\u00a0"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "Which Olympian had polio as a child, losing the use of her left leg?", "Options": ["Peggy Fleming", "Babe Didrikson", "Wilma Rudolph", "Nandia Comaneci"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "At the 1984 Olympics, which athlete won the same races as Jesse Owens?", "Options": ["Sebastian Coe", "Carl Lewis", "Bruce Jenner", "None of the above"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "Who competed in seven Olympic events in eight days and won each time?", "Options": ["Mark Spitz", "Sebastian Coe", "Matthew Biondi", "Jesse Owens"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "Who is the oldest-ever competing Olympian?\u00a0", "Options": ["Dara Torres", "Wilma Rudolph", "Hiroshi Hoketsu", "Oscar Swahn"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "Which of the following groups could neither watch nor particpate in the Olympics?", "Options": ["Married women", "Slaves", "Foreigners", "All of the above"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "What is the long-distance race known as the marathon named for?", "Options": ["The swift-footed Greek god of messengers", "The hometown of Dikon, the track superstar of his day", "A town north of Athens, where the Athenians won an important battle against invading Persians", "None of the above"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "What were winners of Olympic events crowned with?", "Options": ["Wreathes of laurel", "Chaplets of wild olive", "Circlets of gold", "None of the above"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "What is an\u00a0olympiad?", "Options": ["An athlete competing in the Olympic games", "An ancient Greek unit of time", "A  famous statue of the Greek hero Herakles that athletes rubbed for luck\n", "A maths quiz"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "Olympia, site of the games, was also home to one of the seven wonders of the ancient world. Which wonder was it?", "Options": ["The ivory, gold-adorned statue of Zeus sculpted by the legendary Phidias", "The Olympic Stadium", "The Colossus of Rhodes", "None of the above"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "To be eligible to compete in the games athletes had to:", "Options": ["Train faithfully for ten months before the games, remain under the eyes of officials for a month, and take an oath that they had fulfilled the training requirements", "Train faithfully for ten months, sacrifice a ram to Zeus, and take an oath to bring honor to their city-state", "Win contests at smaller festivals, train faithfully for ten months, and fast for three days before the games", "All of the above"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "Who is called 'Father of Modern Olympics'?", "Options": ["Claus Sluter ", "Jacques Morel", "Jacques Androuet du Cerceau", "Pierre de Coubertin"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "Name the only city to have hosted the modern era Olympic Games three times (at 2016)? ", "Options": ["London", "Athens", "Berlin", "Los Angeles"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "The marathon's odd distance was established in the 1908 Olympics by the measurement from ______ to the finish line so that the Ruler's children could witness the start.", "Options": ["\u00a0Eiffel Tower", "Brandenburg Gate", "\u00a0Windsor Castle", "The Colosseum"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "Waldi at Munich 1972, Wenlock at London 2012, and Vinicius at Rio 2016 are the respective Olympic _______.", "Options": ["Presidents", "Mascots", "Bottled water sponsors", "Stadiums"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "Women were prevented from participating in the earliest Olympic games other than _______", "Options": ["Wrestling", "Swimming", "Gymnastics", "Owning horses"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "The host cities of the Summer Olympic Games 1968 to 1980 all begin with", "Options": ["S", "M", "L", "T"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "Originally the Olympic Games were held every four years because __________ in the other three years.", "Options": ["Superstition", "Wars", "Pilgrimages", "Other games"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Notes": "Mark Spitz of the USA won seven swimming gold medals, including four individual, all in record times at the 1972 Munich Olympics. Michael Phelps of the USA won eight swimming gold medals at the 2008 Beijing Olympics and thus set a new record for the maximum number of gold medals in a single Olympic Games in the history of the Olympics.", "Question": "Who set a record for the most gold medals in a single Olympic Games at the 1972 Munich Olympics?", "Options": ["James Connelly\u00a0", "Nadia Comaneci\u00a0", "Abebe Bikila\u00a0", "Mark Spitz"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "Who was the first winner in modern Olympics?", "Options": ["Mark Spitz\u00a0", "Nadia Comaneci\u00a0", "James Connelly", "Abebe Bikila\u00a0"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Notes": "On September 5, 1972 at the Munich Olympics, the Palestinian terrorists invaded Israeli quarters in the Olympic village killing two players and taking many others hostage. Eleven more Israeli players were killed in a crossfire between the German police and the Palestinians belonging to the Black September group. Even though several countries demanded the immediate closure of the Games, the Olympics continued.", "Question": "Which is the 'Black September Day' in Olympic history?", "Options": ["September 1, 1972\u00a0", " September 5, 1972", "September 1, 1984\u00a0", "September 5, 1984\u00a0"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Notes": "Beijing has hosted the 2008 Summer Olympics and it will host the 2022 Winter Olympics.", "Question": "Which city is the first in the world to be awarded both summer and winter Olympics?", "Options": ["Seoul", "Tokyo", "Beijing", "Atlanta"], "Answers": "C"}]